# Aleix López Data Scientist | Particle Physicist

cheals@outlook.com

677020257

Barcelona, Spain

Hard-working physicist with competitive qualifications who has decided to change his path from academic research in particle physics to data science. Proficient knowledge in statistics and Python (6 years of experience). Self-taught data scientist with experience in Kaggle competitions. Willing to join a fast-moving and challenging environment.

## **EDUCATION**

# **BSc in Physics** Universitat de Barcelona

09/2013 - 07/2017

- Description
- Major in Fundamental Physics.
- Upper Second Class Honours.

# MSc in High Energy Physics, Astrophysics and Cosmology

Universidad Autónoma de Barcelona

09/2017 - 09/2018

- Description
- High Energy Physics itinerary.
- First Class Honours (8.7/10).
- Statistics and Data Analysis projects.

# **Data Science Self-Education** Open Source

09/2018 - Present

- Description
- High-quality education from MOOCs, OpenCourseWare, ebooks, Stack Overflow, GitHub and Kaggle.
- Practice with data science projects.
- + 2000 hours.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Kaggle competitions Kaggle

09/2018 - Present

Active participant in Kaggle competitions in order to practice with endto-end projects and keep up with the state-of-the-art algorithms and methods. https://www.kaggle.com/aleixlopez.

#### Writer

## Towards Data Science

06/2019 - Present

Sharing concepts, ideas and codes about data science, machine learning, programming, visualization and AI. https://medium.com/@aleixlopez.

## **SOFT SKILLS**

Resiliency | Versatile | Time management | Requires minimal supervision | Self-Motivation | Competitive | Verbal and written communication | Critical thinking | Reasoning | Problem solving | Identify and predict trends and patterns | Report writing | Scientific programming

## TECHNICAL SKILLS



# PROJECTS AND PUBLICATIONS

My Portfolio: https://aleixlopezpascual.github.io/

 Some of the projects: Hypothesis Testing and Unfolding; Parameter Estimation and Bayesian Statistics; Probability and Monte Carlo Techniques; End-to-end project with Logistic Regression

## **LANGUAGES**

Spanish			
Catalan			
English			